Wait, put your hands together, please.
Hello, everyone.
I'm Karl Sakaki.
I make feeling in Japan.
I'm very happy to be invited to the summit.
So since I'm not really used to English,
I'll be switching back to Pixelogic Daisuke
to be the translator for this presentation.
So I want to introduce you to the workflow,
what I do to make figurines in Japan.
So I would like to show you some introductions of my work
for some showcases of what I do as a work.
So this work is representing, well, this work is for the book itself,
and this is showcasing a lot of like ZBrush techniques in the book.
This is a figurine of Kaguya Luna.
It's a popular character in Japan, and this was made by Wonderful Works,
which is his company, and this is one of his like figurines of his company's work.
So this was ordered by Kotobukiya and made by him.
So this is a figurine which just came out yesterday in Japan, I guess?
And it is his latest work on Wonder Festival.
No. Sorry.
Wonderful Works. Sorry.
So this character is from Liza's Atoria, and this is coming out on September 26th?
Yes.
And yeah, so this is the main character of the game.
This is the first image you saw is like 1 7th of the scale, but this is the human scale,
so full scale shown on Tokyo Game Show.
So his company and his work will do like a lot of scales, like big human size scales and small scales which you can buy and store it in your house.
So for this presentation, he will be showcasing you the same character artists, character designer who did the Liza's Atoria's character.
Toridamono-san, and this character was designed by himself, and this is one of his original characters, Kimaira-chan.
So this is the 3D data for the character he just showed you.
So he will be showcasing you first how he made the cloths.
He will first make the character's base, then he will pose it first, then after that he will make the cloths.
Then, hello.
Um...
T-PoseとかA-Stanceとかの状態から先に服とかを作ってその後にポーズを取るという方法もありますしそうやっている方もいらっしゃいますけど自分の場合は先にT
-Poseで服を作り始めると無駄に作り込んじゃうとフィギュアの場合は必ず左右非対称になるので左右対称の状態でそこまでも作らなくていいと
ほどほどでポーズを取っていけばいいんですけど自分がちょっと貴重な性格もあって無駄に作り込んじゃうのでそういったことが無駄なのでもうポーズを取ってから服を作るようにしています
So a lot of artists use T-Pose or A-Poses
So then you build the whole character itself and then after that
you pose with the clothes on
but for his workflow mainly he
the final pose itself is asymmetric
so it's not symmetric
so he thinks that he would be better off
making some cloths just after doing some poses
So he's using masks and extract functions
to actually make some cloths
and he will just show you how to make some cloths from itこのマスクの段階は大まかな当たりだけ取れればいいのであまり細かいところまで正確に書かなくても大丈夫です
So he's just making some rough shapes from the body itself
and he doesn't really go into detail for the mask itself
So he's fine with this result
and he's going to go through the extraction function
So when applying the extract function
you put off the double option and the thickness option to zero
so you don't have any thickness on the model
厚みとかは後でつけるのでまずは厚みのない状態で作りましてこれでマスクのところから切り出されたエクストラクターのメッシュが出るんですけどこれがマスクより大きくなっちゃうのでこれをエッジループのエッジループマスクのボーダーで切り取ります
So he will apply the thickness afterwards
and since the extract function will take out
a bit more bigger area than the actual mask itself
he will apply some deletes
to actually remove the additional parts of the masking itself
So after that he will go through the zero-remesher functions
because he had some polygroups on and after that he is going to first put a higher setting on the polycounts
Then after getting the results he is going to reduce the polycounts for a better control
多めのポリゴンからポリゴンの流れを整えつつ少ないポリゴンに減らしていきます
So since like if you have a character's body and if you have a spine going through the middle you want the middle to be like a
completely in the middle of the part
So you control this by applying a split on the polygroups
Then after that you apply a zero-remesher with it
So when applying the zero-remesher
he wants a better topology on the model
so he doesn't want a spiral on the model itself
Now this is a lower polycounts you can see from the model
Why do you like this?
Polygon's流れを気にしているかというとこれは例えば悪い例のポリゴンの流れなんですけど後ろのここですねこことかに三角ポリゴンとかが集中したりしているところがあるんですけどこういうところに対してスカルプト例えばここをディバイドして服の塩を入れようと思ってスカルプトした場合にスムースとかを使うと
ポリゴンに引っ張られて形が崩れてしまうところがどうしても出てしまいます
So you might wonder why he's taking so much time to consider the topology itself
and this is one of the reasons
and this is a bad example
and you can see it from the topology
it's not clean
and if you don't have the clean topology
and if you sculpt on top of it
you will lose the details
and you don't really get the clean result you want
and that is one of the reasons why he takes a bit of time to actually clean up the topology
So on the left you can see it's the first topology result which is high poly counts
and in the middle you have middle poly counts with the poly groups
and then you refine that with on the right hand side model
and that is the final result
and this is what the base mesh would be like for the sculpting for the after process
So since when you sculpt on a flat one-sided polygons
it's not really going to get a good result
so you will apply a thickness right now
厚みをつけるときはVModelerのエクストルードではなくてMorphターゲットの機能を使いますなぜかというとVModelerのエクストルードで厚みをつけるとこれですね内側の方のポリグループが全部一緒になってしまうのでこれを避けたいので表も裏も同じポリグループになるようにMorphターゲットの機能を使います
So you may know ZBrush has a couple of ways
to add thickness to the model, but he
is going to use MorphTarget to make the thickness.
One of the reasons is that when you use Demodeler
to add extrude, it's only going to generate one polygroup
in the inside of the mesh.
So you can see that it was generating red polygroups
inside the mesh.
So he used the store-morph function
to actually store the initial mesh.
And then he uses a transpose inflate function
to adjust the thickness.
And looking at the units of the transpose units,
he is considering how much thick the model will get
get after applying a create div function.
So after pressing the create div, you have a model which has
the thickness.
So after applying the flip,
you can see from the top that there was a huge hole in the middle of the cloth,
but when you're making a figurine, you want that kind of like hole to be closed.
So he did some like Dmulder's close hole function to actually close these kind of holes,
and you now have a firm piece of cloth to actually sculpt on.
So you can see from the model that the crease is applied.
So he was demonstrating first, he applied the divide function without the crease,
and it was getting really, really rounded.
But after you apply the crease, you have a more sharper edge on the result.
So after the base mesh is done, he will be sculpting the details of the cloth,
and he will store all the details in the layer function.
So he's using his custom-made brush, which is available on Gumroad,
and he's using the SK-cloth brush.
So he's using a wide stroke first, then after making the broad strokes,
then you make a brush smaller, then you get into detail to actually make the folds.
And one question, how many of you use SK brushes?
Thank you.
A couple, you guys.
Thanks.
Just Google SK brush or Sakaki Kaoru, and you will see a Gumroad shop,
and then you can download his entire IMM brushes and the entire SK-cloth and SK-clay fill.
And it's really useful for figurines.
I think Toma will post a URL for the Gumroad.
Yeah.
So there is one brush he would like to recommend.
It's a brush called Smooth-Groove Brushes.
Smooth-Groove Brushes.
So there is one brush he would like to recommend.
And which is located inside the Lightbrow box and in the Smooth Folder.
And you can see it from the file.
And if you click it, there will be a brush for it.
So, when you apply the Smoothie brush to add the Curvepoint brush,
you can see theст
but it makes it enormistles.
This is with your edge when we release anymore.
So when you apply the Smoothie brush,
So when you're applying the smooth brush, and if you normally apply a smooth brush, the corners of the mesh will get rounded, but since you're using a smooth group brushes, and he's applying a separate group on the edge of the model, like the thickness of the corner of the model,
so when he uses the smooth group brushes, it's not going to affect the different polygroup type of the model.
So there is another brush you want to recommend. It's a smooth directional brush, which is located in the lightbox, smooth, and you can find it there.
And this brush will consider which direction you're moving your brush, and then smooth the model accordingly.
So if you want the cloth to follow those kind of strokes, then you can clean it up after that.
So if you use a normal smooth brush, it will make, like, after you apply a fold to it, then use a smooth brush.
It will, like, shrink the details after you sculpted, so it will, like, it will get rid of your sculpt after you sculpted, but when you use the smooth directional brush, it's going to maintain those kind of details.
So since smooth directional brush will just consider the brush stroke directions, it's going to maintain the details, which was...
what you wanted to sculpt in the first place.
So we can fill it, like, over the same time.
This brush, I'll get rid of it.
So let me make sure the seamless brush are done with it.
These parts of the advantages are already Avengers.
This is When you start with fluid Advisory.
Okay, so you can draw this to help you manage biggerg空中 and acting.
This is fun because of this match .
It's OK.
It's ok.
If I push these part of the line.
So one of the reason why he used the layer function is that he wanted to store this kind of like roundness afterwards on the cloth's edge.
So if you apply some like polish afterwards, you can store it differently in a different layer.
So he made a secondary layer on the model.
So he's like applying some polish or the smooth on the corner of the model.
So you can have the roundness stored separately on the model.
So he just selected the thickness part of the model and then apply a mask to it and then reverse it, apply a blur to it and then applying some control to it.
So he applied a smooth on top of it.
Move.
So he also applied a roundness using a move brush.
So after selecting the thickness part and then reversing it, then applying a blur to it, then he has a better control
of the roundness and the corners.
Then he wanted to apply a polish on top.
So one of the reasons why he's doing this is that if you just have a thickness and without the roundness, it feels like a mech part and it's not like the cloth you're looking for.
So this is one of the reasons why he's applying this kind of actions onto the model.
So since he has a separate layer just storing the roundness of the corners, now if you apply some smoothness,
groups to make that kind of like corners accidentally round, but since it's stored separately, it's going to maintain that kind of roundness and you have a better control over it.
So using this kind of like layer functions makes your model kind of like robust compared to the stuff you're required to do.
Like if you have a design change of the model, you can do it non-destructively and effectively.これが最終的にできたデータで、まずここにシワのレイヤーが入って、厚みを丸めるレイヤー、あとはここのライン状のディティールのレイヤーと全部分けて入れてあります。
これが最終的にできたデータで、まずここにシワのレイヤーが入って、厚みを丸めるレイヤー、あとはここのライン状のディティールのレイヤーと全部分けて入れてあります。
So you can see there's several layers that stores several kind of details, like the folds itself, the lines and the broad strokes of the model.以上が服の自分の作り方です。
以上が服の自分の作り方です。
So this is the cloth process that he usually do.
Any reactions?
Any questions?
Any claps?
Any reactions?
Yeah.
Thank you.
So next he will be showing you how to make the hairs for the figurines.
髪の毛はIMMブラシを使って作成していきます。IMMブラシも自分の制作したカスタムブラシでSKHairっていうブラシを用意しています。
So for the hairs, he's going to use the IMM brushes, IMMカーブ brushes, and he has his own set of custom IMM brushes.
It's called SKHair, which is included in the Gumroad's download link if you can share it.
Yeah, done.
Okay.
That's included in the pack.
So yeah, you can download it.まず今このように頭に対して髪の毛のラインを1本引こうとするとこのように髪の毛の草が1本できます。これは少し動かしたり、あとはブラシサイズで太さを変えたり、あとはこのVintensityの部分で、
厚みを変えたりできますので、これでこのイラストにあった部分を変えたり、まず、このように頭に対して髪の毛のラインを1本引こうとすると、このように髪の毛の草が1本できます。これは少し動かしたり、あとはブラシサイズで太さを変えたり、あとはこのVintensityの部分で厚みを変えたりできますので、
これでこのイラストにあった髪の毛の幅とか太さとかをまずざっくりと調整します。
Also as you know, IMM Car Brushes allow you to change the thickness using the Z-Intensity settings
and you can change the thickness or the size of the brush itself by using the size sliders.
So he's adjusting and looking at the illustration itself and comparing that and making the first initial hair shine.
正確な形状はこのカーブ上で調整せずに後からムーブブラシで動かしていくので、まずは大まかにだけカーブを配置するようにしています。
So he's going to adjust it later using the Move Brushes.
So he's now just making some broad strokes and basic shapes using the IMM Curves.
で、IMM Curveを使うときの注意点として、このベースの頭の方のオブジェクトに対しては、サブディビジョンレベルとか、先ほど必要に作っていたレイヤーとかは全て無しにしないとIMM
Curveは作れないので注意してください。
So one of the restrictions in the IMM brushes is that you can't really use a subdivision mesh
on the base of the, like for example on the head itself.
You can't really apply a subdivision or a layer.
So you need to store that kind of like subtool separately.
So usually you just duplicate the subtool and delete all those kind of like data.
And you just use that as a base mesh and delete it afterwards
if you apply some IMM Curves.で、日本のフィギュアで求められるのはキャラクターの絵にどれだけ似てるかっていうのが求められますので顔に対しての髪の毛の割合とか長さとか毛先の位置とかというのをきっちりと絵に合わせるように心がけながらこのようにムーブブラシで位置を調整します。
一方のものを日本のフィギュアで求められるのは日本のフィギュアで求められるのはキャラクターの絵にどれだけ似てるかっていうのが求められますので顔に対しての髪の毛の割合とか長さとか毛先の位置とかというのをきっちりと絵に合わせるように心がけながら
こんなふうにムーブブラシで位置を調整します。日本のアーティストが多く問われているのはイルストレーションに対応する必要があります。3Dモデルに対応する必要があります。
このようにブラシで調整していくんですけれども
例えば先ほど言った絵に合わせるという点では髪の毛の表と裏の境目とかこういうところに模型を使って今位置調整をしています。なぜかというとこちらの今作ろうとしているイラストの絵を見るとイラストの髪っていうのは裏面が描かれることはほとんどないですね。表面しか描かれないので
3Dだからといって安易に裏面が見えるような配置の仕方をするとなんか似てないねっていうふうになるのでそういったことがないように注意しています。So
one tips that he's gonna give that when making or considering the hairs, you can't really make
the hairs really really thick.Especially on the side hairs,
if you make the hairs thick and because the 3D
requires to do those kind of stuff,
you can't really make the thickness really big
because it will be really not close to the illustration.
And illustration usually has a thin one stroke of a line
for the thickness of the hairs.
So you need to replicate those kind of thickness to the 3D.And
you have a lot of ways to flip the hairs strands
to make it look thin or combining with the other hairs to make it stabler.And
those kind of like tips will be shown here.
そこからIMMブラシで髪の毛の配置をしていった後の状態がこのようになります。So
this is basically the rough shape after the IMM brushes are set.And this will
be the base mesh
for the process he's going to show afterwards.この状態だとこのIMMブラシで配置した毛の一本一本は今のところまだ全部離れています。So
in this case you can see
thatone strand of the hair is separate polygroups.So you can see like
one polygroup is applied on one strand.
このようなIMMブラシで作っているときに毛先とかを尖らせたいという場合があると思いますけどそういった場合で一番簡単なのは毛先だけマスクしてそれをブラーその上でトランスポーズかギズモでもいいんですけどもスケールで細くしてあげるとこうやって毛先を尖らせることが簡単になります。So
one tip you can use when you are making the hairs
like look sharp you can mask the tip of the hairsand
then apply a scale to itto
make it really really thin and sharp.Gizmo
is okay.You can use
like the transpose.he uses transpose
because he's an oldtime zebra schuza
and like a lot of artistslike to use transpose or
gizmo so you can use both
and it's basically the same.If
you apply mask and then scale it, it's the same result.で、ここから作り込んでいくときにこのままディバイドしてこうやってディテールを入れていくのではなく自分の場合はまずダイナメッシュで全部くっつけてしまいます。
So of course there is a way just after this like applying a divide on top of the modeland
then going directly to the details but he doesn't do this kind of stuff.
で、ダイナメッシュのレゾリューションの数値ですけれどもこれ自体に必ず毎回いくつっていう数値が決まってるわけじゃなくて作るものの大きさとポリゴンの細かさによって毎回数値はちょっと変わってます。で、大体今お見せしているような細かさぐらいであればいいかなっていうので感覚で数値を選んでます。
So you can see that he applied a Dynamesh onto the hairs firstand
then he explained thatwhen
you're choosing the resolutionsDynamesh
doesn't really have a set resolutionit's depending on
the size of the modeland you can see
a whole new video about this kind of stuffin the Ask Zrush
section done by Josephbut the size of the modelhas
a huge impact on the Dynamesh
result
and so he's eyeballing the resultand
like seeing how much of the resolution he needs to apply to the mesh
ここからくっつけたところの溝を滑らかに埋めていくんですけれども通常のスムースですと結構ハイポリゴンになっているのでならすのが大変です。そこで自分がよく使うのはこれも自分のカスタムブラシですけれどもSKクレイフィルっていうブラシを使います。
so he is applying a smooth on top of the hairsbecause
the original IMM brush hairshas
separate kind of strandsand
you don't want those kind of strands really really separatelyand
you want some strands to showbut
you want some of the bumps and the segments to be non-visible
so you are applying a Dynamesh for that reasonand
he is filling those kind of like separationsusing
his own SKクレイフィルto
fill up those kind of like segmentsso
you can see some of the hair strands now looks more unifiedso
it's now one part
ブラシの効果まで説明しましたこのブラシはSKクレイフィルhas
a functionthat he is
likewhen applying a Dynameshand
if you apply
a smooth on top
of itbecause it's a high
resolutionit's really hard to controland clean up
the bumps
but like he combined thehe
used the function of a clayand
using that to fill up the segmentsand
make it easy for the high resolution meshto
be able to be filled and managed and controlledSKクレイフィルでこのように
えっとSKクレイフィルでこのようにえっとおまかに溝を埋めていってえっと最後に細かい凹凸のところだけえっと凸凹だけはえっと通常のスムースでならしていきますでこのときえっとまあスムースかかってんのかかかってないのかよくわかんないんですけどえっとキーボードの1を連打するこれはリピートストロークでしたっけ
で前と同じストロークの動作をするのでえっとまあ要するにスムースを何十回も同じようにかけているという効果が現れるのでダイナメッシュでやっているようなハイポリゴンに対してもスムースがかかりやすくなります
本当に少しなきゃいけないなさらに切り替わりの嘴かんでせる
smooth brush, and then you can use the one key on the keyboard, like one. So it
repeats the brush stroke you've done just before, so it will just repeat the
same smooth on top of the places where you just apply the smooth on so just
pressing the one key will just repeat the stroke of the smooth so it makes the
and the bumps disappear.
So now he's going to go to the detail of the hair
and he is using an SK slash brush for these kind of strokes.
So the way he goes about sculpting the details,
first he applies the basic strokes,
which is shown on the illustration itself.
And you can see this like sandable sign on the hair,
but because this was really visible on the illustration,
it's a key part of the character.
So he's applying this kind of like key design first,
then after that he's going to go to the details
to actually apply some strokes afterwards.
So,
So, if you just follow along the illustrations, like key designs, there's like a lot of parts that feels like bland, that you need more details on top of it.
That is the part where the figurine artist can thrive, that you can apply some details that you can apply from the stuff that is not on the original illustrations.
So you can see from how he did the strokes, like if you apply the strokes on the edge of
the hair, so you can see it just applying a C curve, and this looks like a segment between
the front and the back of the hair.
So you need to be careful that this looks like a thickness of the model, the thickness
of the hair itself.
So where you draw this kind of like harsh line makes the difference between the thick hair
and the thin hair.
This is kind of the illusion we're working on, like this is like you are making it really
look flat, but it's not actually flat, and like some of the stuff is like really like
illusional in a way in Japanese figurines.
エッジを入れるところの位置も気をつけて、このように表面だけが見えるような
エッジのつけ方にして、さらにまだ裏面がちょっと見えるような形になっているので、ここですね今動かしてるところですけども、ここを奥に引っ込めることで正面から見て、なるべく裏面が見えないように。
So now he wants to consider how much the back of the hair is visible from the front.
So he's applying a mask, and then controlling where the separation between the front and the back occurs.
So after applying some details, this is the final result he got.
So you can see some of the details is not really visible on the illustrations.
So he applied it himself, and this is where he looks at the character's designs and considers what kind of details he can add.
So first of all, we're going to see how much the back of the hair is visible.
Why do you think that the hair is visible?
they get it or anything.
Objects are all different.
It may be synced by all of the objects.
It will be connected to all of the objects that are connected to all of the objects.
If you're at the figure design,
you can make it in the same way.
In fact, it's not an option to make it similar to you.
So, as you can see, on the back of the characters, there is no separation line on the character, like there is no separation on the back of the hair, right?
So, this is the reason mainly why he wants the Dynamesh to be applied in the hair.
And there is a couple of figurine artists in Japan who likes the hair to be split, but he wants this to be unified, so he has better control of the shadows of the model if the light is cast.
So, this is the whole presentation itself.
So, he is fine with the questions. If you have any questions, I can translate it.
I can't see where you are, I am sorry. Did I hurt you? I got a good lawyer.
I am Logan. You mentioned earlier that you do all your stuff asymmetrically. Do you actually have, do you ever come across a reason to do it, say, in an A pose?
A pose? A pose?
A pose? A pose.
例えば、対象に作らないといけないモデルだったりとか、Aポーズとか、基本的なポーズを求められるようなモデルはあったか?
I was told by being an action figure,動くフィギュアはもちろん左右対象のままで、他にはメカのパーツとかですね。
If you have a little bit of a Meka-like design, you can make it in a stance, and then move it into a pose.
So for the action figurines, you can see that it's really basic pose, the initial pose.
and those kind of figurines
and like
for the characters which has
mech parts
those kind of mech parts are
really
needs to be symmetrical but
he's applying
those kind of like parts
afterwards
first making it symmetrical then
splitting apart to the
poses
which needs to be placed so he's applying
the parts
he made afterwards to the pose
itselfもう一つ言うと自分の仕事だとクライアントがいて修正の指示をされるというケースが多いので先ほど言った左右対称のパーツもせっかく腕に配置したのにちょっと直してと言われて左右対称の形状に戻ってまた持ってくるというのが
何度も繰り返されるということがありましたあまりにもそれが多いんでその時は腕の方に板ポリを配置してナノメッシュで配置する
という方法を取りました
so his work
has a client
and his client
sometimes require him
to do some
rethinking
or redo
on the model
and
there was one case
that he had
a lot of retakes
and he had to
use the nanomesh
to replace that part
so nanomesh
will make an instance
of the mesh
and you put
a flat plane
polygon
on top of it
and then replace
that part
with the nanomesh
so there was one case
that he had to do that
it's a nice little trick there
go ahead
oh yes
I'm asking for my sensei
you're asking
shoe sensei
yes
he was asking
about like
the nanomesh
of the back of the hair
when you're like
doing actual
3D printing
do you have to do it
in dynamesh
or
would you
would you like
remesh it a bit
or the final result
should be
so he just applies
the dynamesh
and then afterwards
then if he has
the final result
he would just
use the decimation master
to decimate it
and then
that would be
the final result
so it's okay
to use the animation
of course
yeah
the final result
is going to be
handled through
the decimation master
so that it can be
processed through
the 3D printing
at that point
it's going to leave
ZBrush anyway
and go into
proprietary software
smarter than I look
hold on
hi
my name is Nabil
that was a
great work
but I have a question
like
you don't feel like
you're limited
like for example
like to do
to the 2D
like line
some lines
are like
not intentional
they're like
just happy accident
you don't feel
like you're
like attached
to those lines
like for example
in the hair
you were like
following
the lightning
zigzag
like
you don't feel
like you're
like
limited
you don't feel
like you're
like I will
似せる中でも滲み出る個性というか、すごく似てるんだけど、このデザイナーが作ったなって分かるような個性がフィギュアにそれぞれ出てくるので、
みんなに好まれる造形をしつつも、坂木香織が作ったなっていうような個性っていうのを分かるようにできればいいなと思っているので、作ってるのはすごく楽しいです。
So there is some Japanese artists who don't like to follow the illustration's likeliness entirely,
or they will keep some part of it and then they will put their original taste to it.
But he likes to follow the illustration's likeliness first, then apply some original taste to it,
which is not really like a limitation, it's more, what do you call those, spice to it?
It's more like a secret additive.
Secret sauce.
Yeah, then it's like a bleeding personality coming out from the figurines.
So if the client likes his figurines and if the client likes his taste of the figurines,
then it will be good for him as an artist because no one else can replicate his kind of taste
with the same characters or the same illustration he's given.
Right, good secret there.
Amas Roussel, Pixelogic.
Go ahead, take it away.
He's got a question.
Is this a question?
No, in fact, it's not my question, but online a lot of people are wondering who dance
are such models, the polygon count, because it looks very, let's say, very simple surfaces,
but you have some very controlled curves.
Then you need to have a lot of polygons while it looks simple.
Then how many polygons do you have on such models?
And how does it manage also this polygon count while it's working?
Male Speaker 2
No affecting companies.
Well,甜 Эgitter.
What is it on?
That's what I am doing.
Maybe there are some points of service.
So is that the one sub tool or global?
No, not every single part of it.
I'm just going to have a drawing.
Do you think it's a legend of what I'm trying to contribute to that?
And this thing is the one sub tool or global.
This has 10 million polygons for the back of the head.
So he doesn't really look at the polycount itself.
You can see it in the UI, you can't find the polycounts.
So yeah, he was talking about 20 million polygons.
So it's 20 million?
20 million polygons for the total.
So he will be ending up likely that kind of amount.
That's not so crazy.
No, it's reasonable.
Hey, so this book that's sitting here on top of the desk, people inquiring minds want to know,
is this book available in the United States?
Yeah.
Yeah, of course, and through Amazon, of course, right?
You can search his name and just type book and this will come up.
Okay, we got one in the front row.
Go ahead.
Joey here.
When you're reviewing the concept art of the illustration for reference, what part of that helps the most?
So is that a reference which the client asks you or the additional references you add to them?
Yeah.
How about the reference is applied?
Like an illustration or something like that.
Clientが送ってくる人とかそういう感じの資料ですか?
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah.
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah
So, a couple of things, one is the pose, and one is the scale of the characters, like body parts, like if they...
Usually, Japanese artists like considers the head is the one scale, so usually one scale is equivalent of the arm itself, and so he is looking at these kind of like scales and what kind of ratio this kind of like part has.
So, he will look at the pose, how is the model looking like, and then the scale differences of the parts.
And he will use those kind of information from the reference.
Way in the back here. Let's hear it.
I was interested in understanding if he is responsible for the parting of the model for the production, or is that handed off to someone else on his team?
So, he does do the separation himself.
So, since this is a team effort, like sometimes he's really, really busy with the other subject or really tight, have a tight schedule, he will hand it off to the other teams or the other workers he has.
So, yeah, in some cases, it happens.
Okay, cool. Got another one back here. Let's hear it.
When you were first starting out 3D sculpting, did you have your own illustrations that you were drawing based off of, or did you just choose your most favorite drawings online and start sculpting from there?
3Dの造形を始めた時に自分の描いたイラストを元にしたのか、それとも他の作品のイラストを元にして作ったのか。自分が3D始めた時から他の人のイラストを元に作ってます。
So, from the start, when he started doing some 3D sculpting, he started off by using other people's character designs.
And he, because one of the reasons why he does this is that he didn't have the good figurine which he was looking for, for his favorite characters.
So, that's why he started making the figurines himself.
Okay, put your hands together.
Akeoru Sakaki, as the smoke rises and fills the room.
Oh yeah, thanks a million.
That was one heck of a presentation, man.
Really appreciate it.
Okay, and this presentation was actually brought to you by...
Mikaki.
Did I say that right?
Say it again?
Mimaki.
I've been trying to say that right all day.
Not Takate.
Mimaki.
This is where my head's at.
It's almost party time, people.
Okay, so, we've got some giveaways happening now.
Live from the Nomen School of Visual Effects here inside the green screen hanger.
The same great taste, the same great place.
I'm Louis Tucci, your host for the Zebra Summit 2019.
I hope you're enjoying yourselves at home, tapping away on the keyboard.
It's really great.
Completely appreciate the support.
Here inside the house.
One more time, put it together.
Saturday.
If not now, then when?
Thank you.
Okay, they wanted to get my voice a little more clear inside the building here.
The house speakers.
Can you guys hear me okay?
They're gonna do...
What's all this about?
He's signing the thing.
And a hush comes over the...
We have an extra on-site giveaway happening here.
He is signing.
Can you dig...
Put your hands together.
Somebody's gonna walk away with the hardware.
Wow.
And the book too.
Here we go.
They're hiding the book.
Okay.
Yeah, we have extra...
Can you guys hear me?
Oh yeah.
Okay, I have an extra giveaway for you guys here.
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls...
This is an extra prize.
This is...
So you don't have to choose the number.
We've already chosen for you.
Okay, are you ready?
Looking for 699-084.
Come on.
Come on down!
084.
Tomas, you're not eligible.
Tomas, you are ineligible is the term for that.
You are ineligible, sir.
I don't know how you say that in French, but it's fancy for not available.
You can't do it.
699-084.
Come on down.
Wow, you did it.
Nice jacket.
Look at this.
What?
Michelle, what's happening?
Hold on a second.
You're standing in the middle.
Hi.
What's your name?
Michelle.
Hi, Michelle.
Hi.
Did you enjoy Kyler Sakaki's presentation?
Yes.
Well, good news.
Suddenly she's feeding the heat from the lamps.
You have won a figure sculpted by Sakaki Sand.
This is Bismarck.
Yeah.
Put your hands together.
From Good Smile.
Look at that.
He's giving it to you personally for Pete's sake.
Oh my goodness.
And he signed it for you.
Get the photo op in here.
Oh my goodness.
A grand origato here.
Okay.
Amazing.
Thanks, Michelle.
Enjoy.
Thank you.