In the last video, we generated a geometry cache of the skin using our simulation results.
Next, K underscore email for our muscles, which is dash.
Now, let's go to preview scene.
For a detailed explanation of the parameters, you can review the muscle simulation video
to make sure you have the animal deformer.
Right now, we'll just quickly go through the parameters here.
For this example, you have to use 20 sub-steps and also animal deformer neuromorph model iterations.
If you just have them checked, you should restart editing more layers than just the muscles.
It contains the fat layer, which relies on the movement of the muscles and the multiformer asset.
And that means the deformation on the muscles needs to propagate all the way to the fat layer.
And that requires more solver iterations.
I can double-click to go into the animal deformer asset.
Next, let's go ahead and check do quad aesthetics.
Let's first go to quad aesthetics.
Because we're running a quad aesthetics simulation.
And then make sure we're training on the skin.
So, set the skeletal mesh to be the skin.
Now, we should be able to see the skin.
And over here, we're going to use the gaussetl solver.
For training animation, this is designed for quad aesthetics.
Let's go ahead and give the animation that we ran simulation on.
For now, we're turning off the spring collision.
That would be the major motion simulation.
Because the collision scenario is pretty complicated,
we turn it on as this is the ground truth of the simulation.
And that checks collisions against every single connected geometry group.
Once that's set, we should have a training base and target mesh for training to learn from.
For example, at the elbow.
Next, we should set up the network inputs.
For now, let's skip that.
These are the joints that will serve as inputs to the network.
So, let's go ahead and click this plus button.
Because that's currently incompatible with gaussetl solver.
And for this example, let's just add all animated bones.
And make sure you might want to add only the major bones.
So that the pain in muscles, the biceps, and the lower pectoralis can contract.
Going down here.
For this simulation, let's set the other animation.
Which is the range of motion.
We only have 150 frames.
Coming down here.
Let's set a new cache collection.
Let's set to be 100.
For a fast training.
Now we should be able to see the difference between the fact
and the ground truth, which is our simulation results.
Let's run a little bit longer.
You can see these little line segments.
They represent 5 seconds at 30 frames per second.
So 150 frames in total.
Now we can start training the model.
So now let's hit that red record button to start a simulation.
Once you hit that, the solver should start running in the background.
For some initial setups of the simulation.
You can see that you should be able to see a notification window soon.
There...
Because we have more vertices in the simulation, this should take more time in general.
And also we're using a higher number of sub steps and iterations.
Now the ML deformer is trained.
We can validate the results by going into the testing tab.
Come back later.
Let's go ahead and hit the play.
Let's go ahead and start viewing the simulation.
Pay attention to the lower pectoralis there.
As it's contracting with the arms coming down.
And next thing is also set ground truth.
Compare it with the ground truth.
Something that's pretty useful is this heat map option.
So let's check that.
Now that we have a simulation of the fat.
And that will show you...
Let's transfer the deformation on the fat.
Where the vertex deltas are being applied.
Onto the skin.
Because that's what we'll see eventually.
We can embed the skin into the fat tetrahedral mesh.
Barycentrically.
And interpolate the skin from the simulation results.
So let's go ahead and get back to the data photograph.
You can see when the arms coming down.
We're seeing a lot of the vertex deltas.
From the surface bindings.
Here.
Because we're adding muscle contraction.
To the ground truth.
What this node does.
Is that.
It takes either a static mesh.
Or a skeletal mesh.
And then embeds.
All the vertices.
You can also see a lot of.
Like vertex deltas.
Being applied around the shoulder.
And this is due to.
So let's go ahead and set the skeletal mesh.
To be skin.
Volume preservation.
When the arms coming down.
We're also getting.
Some deformation from elasticity.
On the shoulder.
Because it's being stretched.
To make sure that we connect that.
To the collection.
So we.
We can also.
Use another.
To the fat layer.
So.
Remember we got the fat layer.
From here.
Let's go ahead and set.
The lift weights.
Which is not included.
In the training.
So.
We can safely do it here.
And this time.
Let's get rid of the ground truth.
Because now it's evaluating.
It's finished.
And then connect the collection.
Back in.
Now we can play through the animation.
Remember all the.
Barocentric.
Data.
Stored here.
Will be.
Automatically updated.
Through.
Something to notice.
Is that.
The ground.
This pose.
When the arm is fully bent.
On the appended.
Muscle contraction.
On the bicep.
The reason.
Is that.
In this note.
There is also.
The option.
Of not.
Surface projection.
Remember.
Not all the time.
That.
The skin.
Will be.
Fully.
Therefore.
Is not expected.
To see.
Any bicep.
Contraction.
The scenario.
That.
The skin.
Is.
Provided.
Offset.
So.
Make sure.
That you leave.
This on.
The other.
Range of motion animation.
Those outside.
Slightly outside.
Vertices.
So.
Now.
With this said.
We can go ahead.
And then.
Set up.
The geometry cache generation.
We can see.
Around here.
Embedded.
Sculpture.
Make sure.
There are some extreme.
Elbow bending.
Which is the skin.
And this is really good.
To try and set that.
In order.
For the.
Moldeformer.
Let's go ahead.
And click this.
New geometry cache.
And create.
New geometry.
So the solution.
Is to consider.
Using the whole animation.
As training data.
As it covers.
A lot of.
We're ready to generate.
Our geometry cache.
In general.
You should think about.
What animation.
That you apply.
Onto the character.
For example.
In a game.
And also.
Your training data set.
In a way.
That all possible.
Joint angles.
Are covered.
In the range.
Of the training data.
This should be much faster.
Than the simulation.
Because we're only.
Reading the simulation results.
And interpolating.
The skin positions.
From that.
We can open up.
You can either construct.
A range of mouse.
In training animation.
Like this.
Double click that.
Or generate.
A random pose.
Data set.
Within.
A large.
Joint rotation space.
For more information.
On training.
The ML deformer.
Please refer.
To the ML deformer.
Page.
Linked.
In the description.
And pay attention.
To that.
Let's use.
The train.
ML deformer.
To that.
And you can see.
To find.
ML deformer.
On 150 frames.
Of the bicep curl.
Simulation.
You can check.
The vertex deltas.
The arm.
That's introduced.
So as a recap.
We run.
A quasi-static simulation.
Of the muscles.
And fat layer.
We generated.
A geometry cache.
Of the skin.
From the left.
And the right side.
In the next video.
We use.
The geometry cache.
To train.
An ML deformer.
To start using.
The train.
ML deformer.
Let's go back.
To map.
Correctives.
And then.
On the character skin.
What physics.
And biomechanics.
Enhanced.
Click actor.
And I will rename this to.
Email.
Blueprint.
Let's go ahead and double click.
To open up that.
Blueprint asset.
Click add button.
To add a skeletal mesh.
Component.
For the skeletal mesh.
Let's set it to be.
The skin skeletal mesh.
And also.
We want to turn on.
Mesh deformer.
Make sure to check that.
And then over here.
Under the gear button.
Here.
Make sure you have.
Show engine content.
And show plugin content.
Both enabled.
So that you can see.
The deformer graph.
That we're going to use.
For example.
If you don't have the show engine content.
You will not see any.
Graphs there.
Make sure they're.
They're enabled.
And then we're going to use.
This.
DG underscore.
A multiformer model.
Let's go ahead.
And test this.
On.
An animation.
Select.
Use animation asset.
And then.
For example.
Let's use.
The one.
We trained on.
In this case.
The lip weight animation.
Now.
Let's go ahead.
And add.
The multiformer.
Component.
So.
For.
And over here.
At.
Multiformer.
Asset.
Let's set it to be.
The bicep curl.
Now.
That's pretty much.
Everything.
And then.
We can.
Click.
Compile.
And then.
Save.
The blueprint.
Now.
We can drag.
The blueprint.
Out.
In the map.
I can.
Reset.
It's.
Transforms.
Let's.
Let's go ahead.
And rotate.
A little bit.
So that.
It's facing.
The sun.
For better lighting.
Now.
If we click.
Simulate.
We'll see.
The ml deformer.
Results.
Being applied.
Onto.
The skeletal mesh.
For example.
There.
Let's.
Zoom in.
Onto.
The bicep.
There.
You can see.
Bicep.
Contraction.
There.
And.
That's the end.
Of the series.
Of the tutorial.
Have fun.
Setting up.
Your simulation.