In the last video, we imported all the assets for email and then enabled all the necessary plugins.
Let's go ahead and start setting up our muscle simulation.
First, let me create a folder called FleshAssets.
And in here, let's create our first FleshAsset.
In this one, I'm going to generate a tetraketral mesh for the muscles.
So let's call this Fitmesh Muscle FleshAsset.
Double click that and then say create new data flow.
Click save.
Now we created a blank data flow graph.
Inside the data flow graph, this is where we'll be setting up our muscle simulation.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And then the first thing we're going to do is...
Let's right click and then type skeletal mesh to bring in our skeletal mesh of the skeleton.
So let's type skeleton here and then find our skeleton.
From here, let's convert it to a collection by calling skeletal mesh to collection.
Once we do that, now you should see the geometries.
And then also the attributes here in the collection spreadsheet.
To drive the simulation, we're only going to need the transform from this skeleton.
Because like I said before, we're going to need the animated skeleton to drive the muscles and then the fat.
And eventually transfer deformation onto the skin.
So skeleton transform is all we're going to need.
Let's make sure we click this transforms only button.
Now we should not see the geometry anymore because now it's only the skeleton transform.
Because we're creating a tetrahedral mesh on the muscles, let's bring in the muscle geometry.
Again, the skeletal mesh, but this time it's going to be the muscles.
Here we go.
Now, same thing, let's convert it to a skeleton.
Sorry, a skeletal mesh collection.
Now you should see the muscles.
From this point, create a node called create tetrahedron.
And let's modify the parameter a little bit before we plug everything in.
For this one, let's use tetwild to generate a high-resolution tetrahedral mesh.
And let's make sure we have this coarsen button on.
Because as an initial test, we want to reduce the resolution of the tetrahedron mesh.
We can always change this later and go back here and modify the settings.
But at this point, let's plug in the collection here.
Let's give it the transforms, also the source geometry.
We're going to use the muscles as the source geometry.
So once that's connected, it should take a little bit of time to generate the tetrahedral mesh.
Again, it should have the transforms here.
And then generate a volumetric mesh from this surface mesh here.
Remember, the muscles are only a surface mesh.
Now that's done.
You should be able to see the tetrahedral mesh.
This is actually a volumetric mesh.
Great.
We can also transfer the colors from the skeletal mesh to the tetrahedral mesh.
Let's go ahead and do that by calling transfer vertex attribute.
From here, the attribute we want to transfer would be color.
And from collection, let's do the skeletal mesh collection.
You see, once that's connected, we have all the colors transferred to the tetrahedral mesh.
Let's go ahead and save this into a terminal.
Flash asset terminal.
Now, we save this.
Now, everything inside the collection is saved into our flash asset that we can use.
We press F here, and now you should be able to see the saved geometry.
Alright, so in the next video, we'll start using this tetrahedral mesh and start simulating things.
That's true.
And then we tap into the spark.
First we'll come from the Archdiocesanh