And then assign an attribute. Let's call this the inner surface.
And then let's transfer this to the fat layer tetrahedral mesh.
Grab this. Grab a transfer attribute, vertex attribute node.
And then connect the collection here.
In this case, it doesn't matter whether it's a global transfer or a parallel transfer,
because we only have one geometry.
Let's go ahead and see the transfer results.
You can see now the inside is white,
because it's got the attribute transferred to it.
That's good.
And then make sure we replace this collection with the transfer collection
that contains the attribute.
After appending it,
Now, if we go to vertices,
we should be able to see the attribute.
Call it inner surface here.
All right.
Next step is extracting the vertex selection from this attribute.
So we've done similar things.
Let's go ahead and get a collection.
Select by attribute node.
And plug in the attribute key here.
Okay.
And again, for the threshold,
let's make sure it's greater than 0.5.
Now this gives us a vertex selection.
And once we plug in the vertex selection here,
it's only going to bind spring constraints between the inner surface of the fat
into whatever is close to the vertices,
to the selected vertices.
Let's go ahead and connect that.
And the position target stiffness,
let's set that to one for now.
But radius, let's see 0.5.
It's the initial try.
At this point, we can also visualize
these little red dots.
They're pretty short spring constraints.
Although it looks like a dot that's a line connecting.
Two points.
Or two set of vertices.
It's a vertex triangle spring constraint.
Alright.
Let's use this and see what happens in the simulation.
Let's go ahead and connect this to terminal.
Now you can see we have the whole thing here in the simulation viewport.
Check our solver settings.
Okay.
And create another chaos cache collection.
Let's call this one the fat.
Cash collection.
Alright.
Let's start running this and see what happens.
Save this.
And start the simulation.
Alright.
We just got back from our simulation results.
As you can see,
the muscle is bulging.
That's because we didn't change our muscle parameter here.
So let's go ahead and change that.
Over here.
Make sure we're using...
To use the global parameters.
Change the contract volume to two.
To see some extra volume.
And you also see some penetration between muscles and the fat layer.
And that's because the muscle is going through extreme deformation.
Or volume increase.
And also because of the spring stiffness.
So let's go ahead and change the stiffness from one to ten.
Let's see if that helps.
Now let's run again.
Now let's take a look at the simulation results.
Let's find a better angle.
And you can see the biceps start to bulge.
The arm comes up and doing biceps curl.
And the fat layer is driven by the muscle deformation underneath it.
That's good.
And then in the next video, we'll start generating geometry cache from this chaos cache.
And then terrain.
And I'm a deformer with the geometry cache.